Hetul H. Patel

I 206, Shree Nand City VI,

Baroda- Abemdabad Express

Near CTM, Baroda- Ahemdabad Express Highway, New maninagar, Ramol,

Ahemdabad-382449

Mob: 09979868141, 09978175156

Email ID: hetulpatelbpl@gmail.com

To, H.R.Managar

**Subject:** - Application for the Suitable post at your reputed Pharmaceutical Company.

Respected Sir/Madam,

I glad to request you that I want to join your esteemed Company. I have completed my M. Pharm. with specialization in Industrial Pharmacy/ Pharmaceutics at S. K. Patel College of Pharmaceutical Education & Research, Ganpat University, Kherva with 67%. I have also passed the GATE examination with 96 %( 856 rank all over India). I have 5 International Publications.

Presently I am working at Zydus Cadila Health Care Limited, Moraiya in Tablet Manufacturing Division (Dispensing, Granulation, Compression, Incident Handling, CAPA handling, Change Control Handling, Deviation Control)(SAP System Handling for Different area like Loss/Excess, mb31,lt01,lt04 and many more transitions).

I am also a FDA registered Pharmacist for capsule manufacturing Area.

Before that I have worked In Gujarat Liqui Pharmacaps P Limited (Capsule Division-1Year) as a Pharmacist. And also in Bharat Parenteral Limited in Tablet/Hard Gelatin capsule Division.

From my site I promise to perform a best, and will do constructive efforts to your institute if chance is given me to serve. Hoping an affirmative response.

My Detail Educational Qualifications and other information are as described in Curriculum vitae enclosed with this application.

Thanking you Sir/Madam.

Yours Faithfully,

Hetul H. Patel

**Enclosed:** 

1. Curriculum vitae

1

# Hetul H Patel (M.Pharm with more than 3.0 Year Experience in Pharma Industry) (FDA registered Pharmacist)

**Education** Permenant address:

M.Pharm Industrial Pharmacy/Pharmaceutics I 206, Shree nand city,

**E-mail:** hetulpatelbpl@gmail.com Near CTM,

**Contact No.:** (M) 09979868141 New Maninagar,

(R) 09978175156 Ramol, Ahemdabad 382449

#### **OBJECTIVE & SUMMURAY**

More than three years experience along with the notable achievements in administering multiple units consisting of production operations, process quality, project and material management, I have expertise and knowledge in Pharmaceutical Sciences. As a designer and developer of Pharmaceutical Manufacturing / Operational Facilities and Supply Chains, I know how to communicate with others, prioritize projects and stream line operations. I have demonstrated my leadership by working in cohesive, customer-oriented teams. I know my skills can make a difference to the company

#### PRESENT JOB RESPONSIBILITY

- 1. To manufacture products as per regulatory cGMP Mfg guidelines.
- 2. Work allocation as per production schedule.
- 3. Follow instructions as per SOP & implementation of SOP.
- **4.** To update routine documents.
- 5. To prepare day-to-day and weekly production planning.
- **6.** To perform routine work on SAP system.
- 7. Manpower and shift handling & control.
- **8.** Co-ordinations of production activities with dept. like QA, QC, store, Egg.
- 9. Monitor cGMP compliance on shop floor.
- 10. Doing qualification of equipment & area.
- 11. Making SOP
- 12. Making daily logs format.
- 13. Woks allocation as per CAPA activity guidelines.
- 14. Follow the machine maintenance schedule as per PM schedule
- **15.** Production planning and achieving the target as per the Planning.
- 16. Compliance and adherence to cGMP.
- **17.** Documentation and record keeping as per the requirements of Regulatory authorities.
- **18.** Co-ordinations with internal & external departments.

- **19.** .Providing periodic training and evaluating the technicians and workers about cGMP, **SOPs** & methods newer and Technologies.
- **20.** Preparation of monthly report for presentation in monthly Review meeting.

#### **EMPLOYMENT HISTORY**

1. Zydus Cadila Health Care Limited (Novemebr 2014 to still Date)

Area to be Handle: Dispensing, Granulation, Compression, Documentation for Change Control, Deviation, Incident, OOS, OOT

- Working exposure in Tablet section.
- ➤ Narrow theropetic Index tablet production like Warfarin, Olopetedine, Anastrozole, Pramipexole etc.
- Responsibility for In Process in Tablet section like LOD, Weight variation, Friability
- Production Planning for Tablet/Capsule section.
- > To complete the manufacturing records for the batch in process.
- Batch issuing from the store for the manufacturing of the Batch.
- ➤ Manpower handling for the capsules & Tablet section
- 2. Bharat Parenteral Limited (April 2014 to November 2014)
- ➤ Working exposure in Tablet/Capsule section.
- Responsibility for In Process in Tablet section like LOD, Weight variation, Friability
- > To complete the manufacturing records for the batch in process.
- ➤ Batch issuing from the store for the manufacturing of the Batch.

  Manpower handling for the capsules & Tablet section
- 3. Gujarat Liqui Pharmacaps P Limited (From march 2013 to April 2014)
- Pharmacist Supervised 8 hourly operations in the production of capsule.
- Wrote and revised SOPs, planned daily production operations and organized materials and manpower.
- Extensive troubleshooting and resolution of production problems.
- Shree Swaminarayan Pharmacy College, Kevadia Colony (From Auguest 2009 to March 2013)
- Assistant professor, Documentation handling For GTU and PCI

#### **EQUIPMENT HANDLING**

- > FBD (60, 125 kg)
- > RMG (250,450)
- Roll Compactor
- Octagonal Blender
- Cage Blender

- > Egg shell blender
- > Compression machine like

Cadmach CTX 26 station, Cadmach CTX 32 station, Cadmach CTX 45 station

Cadmach CTX 75 station, Cadmach CTX 61 station

- > SQC printer
- > Capsule Filling machine of Solace Engineering, Cadmach
- ➤ Multimill
- > Sifter

#### **EDUCATIONAL QUALIFICATION:**

Course	University/ Board	School/ College	Year of Passing	Academic Grade
M. Pharm	Ganpat University, Kherva, Mehsana	Shree S.K.Patel College of Pharmaceutical Education and Research Center, Kherva, Mehsana	2009	67.5%
GATE	IIT, Kanpur	-	2007	95.32%
B. Pharm	Veer narmad south Gujarat university, Surat.	Rofel College Of Pharmacy ,Vapi	2007	66.15%

## **Personal Profile:**

Mr Patel Hetulkumar Harshadbhai Name

10<sup>th</sup> -April-1986 Date of Birth -

Male Sex **Marital Status** 

Married

Languages known -English, Hindi, Gujarati

Nationality -Indian

## **References**

## Mr. Kalpesh Patil

Zydus Cadila Health Care Limited

Mobile: +91 7600129312

### **Declaration:**

I hereby declare that all the information furnished in my curriculum vitae is true to the best of my belief.